James McNaughton Hester Papers MC.51
New York University Archives
- Speeches and Remarks
  - New York Public Library Annual Dinner (11/16/71), 1971 November-1971 September (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - H. Silverman Testimonial Dinner (11/29/71), 1962, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Trends in Higher Education (United Press International, 12/71), 1971 November-December (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Gallatin Dinner (12/1/71), 1971 November-December (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Real Estate Luncheon (12/2/71), 1971 October-December (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Puerto Rican Commencement (12/4/71), 1971 June-December (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Faculty Club (State University at Farmingdale, 1/6/72), 1972 January 14 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - NYU Faces Critical Issues/Profile of NYU (New York Times, 1/10/72), 1972 January 10 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Tour of the Far East (Faculty Women's Club, 2/72), 1972 March (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Daily News Interview (2/11/72), 1972 February 11 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Road to Rensselaerville (Skidmore College, 2/14/72), 1972 January-February (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Educational Staff Seminar (George Washington University, 2/15/72), 1972 January-February (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Perstare et Praestare (Annual Induction, 2/16/72), 1971 December-1972 January (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Urban Leadership Award Dinner (2/17/72), 1972 February (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Richard Courant Memorial (2/18/72), 1972 February-May (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Ten Years As a University President (The Century Association, 3/2/72), 1972 March-May (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Century Speech, Monthly Meeting, Talk (3/2/72), 1972 March; Reel to Reel tape has not been evaluated by preservation (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Peoria Journal Star, Inc. (Written Remarks, 3/10/72), 1972 January-March (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Lotos Club State Dinner (3/14/72), 1972 January-May (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - New York Times Interview (4/9/72), 1972 April 9 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Peter L. Agnew Office Management Laboratory (4/13/72), 1972 April-May (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Joseph H. Park History Honor Society (5/8/72), 1972 February 7 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Bowery Savings Bank Annual Dinner (5/10/72), 1972 March-May (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - New York Report, WOR TV (5/14/72), 1972 May 14 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - What NYU Can Be, And What It Cannot Be (New York Times Reprint, 5/30/72), 1972 May 30 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - NYU Commencement Address (5/31/72), 1972 May-1973 July (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Statement to Newsweek (6/9/72), 1972 June 9 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Statement to High School Graduates (Rectory of Saints Simon and Jude, 6/14/72), 1972 June (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Radio Program WHWH (6/22/72), 1972 February-June (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Annual Judicial Conference, Lake Placid (6/23/72), 1972 June (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Welcome (Alcohol Recovery Institute, 6/26/72), 1972 January-July (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Faculty Meetings (9/72), 1972 September (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - New York State Education Department Hearings (9/8/72), 1972 September 8 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Testimony for ACUNY Before Legislative Conference of the Board of Regents (9/12/72), 1972 May-September (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - The Present State of NYU (9/18/72), 1972 September 18 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Address to NYU's GSAS Faculty (10/27/72), 1972 October-November (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Crisis in Education: What Really Goes On (Union League Club, 11/1/72), 1972 October-November (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Gallatin Dinner (11/30/72), 1972 November-December (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Urban Leadership Award Dinner (2/8/73), 1973 February (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - WNYU-FM Inaugural Remarks (3/3/73), 1973 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - What is the Future of New York City? (Cotton Fiber Paper Council, 4/73), 1973 January-April (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - King David (Choral Arts Society Narration, 4/15/73), 1973 March-May (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Problems and Prospects of Higher Education in the 70s (Newsweek Corporate Executive Conference, 4/15-17/73), 1973 April (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Dedication of Shimkin Hall (4/18/73), 1973 April (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - College Management Article (5/73), 1973 May (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Guide to Higher Education Today (Women's Council of NY Public Library, 5/2/73), 1973 May (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Introductory Remarks on American Higher Education for Visiting Chinese Journalists (5/22/73), 1973 May 22-23 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Commencement Address (6/5/73), 1973 June 5-7 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Asian-U.S. Educators Conference (IIE) Speech, Thailand (7/16/73), 1973 July (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Parents' Convocation (9/73), 1973 September (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - A New Era and a New Realism (Entering Students at NYU, 9/18/73), 1973 September 18 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Report Card '73 (Radio Interview with John Moergher, 9/23/73), 1973 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 30th Anniversary of Samuel Belkin, President of Yeshiva University (10/73), 1973 October 8 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Catholic Center Mass (10/2/73), 1973 September-October (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Post-Graduate Hospital Alumni Remarks (10/2/73), 1973 October (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Dedication Para-Educator Center (10/3/73), 1973 October 3-4 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Students and Foreign Policy (Foreign Policy Association, 10/10/73), 1973 September-October (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Ethics in Business Education (MAACBA, 10/11/73), 1973 October-December (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Stenger Memorial (10/12/73), 1973 October (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Women's American ORT Greetings (in Writing, 10/21-25/73), 1973 May (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Festschrift - Dr. Julius Mark (10/19/73), 1973 September-November (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Dinner for G. Bugliarello (PINY), Given by A. Eurich (10/31/73), 1973 November 6 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Fall Alumni Meeting and Deans' Day (College of Dentistry, 11/9/73), 1973 November (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Dedication Ceremony at Bellevue Hospital (11/15/73), 1973 November-December (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Brooke Astor Tribute (Lotos Club, 11/15/73), 1973 September-November (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Presentation of Century Club Medallion to Dr. Homer C. Vaughn (11/16/73), 1973 November 16 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - The University and Day Care (11/28/73), 1973 September-December (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Gallatin Dinner (12/4/73), 1973 December-1974 February (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Statement to the Regents of University of the State of New York Concerning Baruch College (12/13/73), 1973 December 13 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Hominids of the African Plio-Pleistocene Conference (1/14/74), 1974 January (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Grace Church School (1/27/74), 1973 September-1974 January (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Rumi-Biruni Conference Opening Remarks (1/28/74), 1973 December-1975 May (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - NYU Spectator Spring Issue Interview (1/29/74), 1974 January (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Medical Alumni Day Remarks (2/23/74), 1973 December-1974 February (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Real Estate Dinner (3/13/74), 1974 March (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Man at the Top (Interview in Organizational Dynamics, Spring 74), 1974 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Are Our Colleges Going Broke? (Change Article Editorial, 4/74), 1974 March-April (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - U.S. News and World Report Interview (4/74), 1974 April-May (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Tamiment Reception (4/16/74), 1974 April-May (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - New Problems in University Management (Association of American Medical Colleges, Phoenix, 4/25/74), 1974 April-1975 March (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Ethics in Business Education (Phi Chi Theta of CBPA, 4/30/74), 1974 April-May (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Dedication of Tinker Coronary Care Unit (4/30/74), 1974 April (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Commerce Dinner (5/6/74), 1974 May 6 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Urban University and Its Community (University Council on Education for Public Responsibility, 5/6/74), 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Commencement Address (6/6/74), 1974 June-August (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Statement Before the Special Subcommittee on Education of the Committee on Education and Labor (8/12/74), 1974 July-1975 March (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Personal Honor (Wake Forest University Convocation, 8/29/74), 1974 August-October (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Freshman Convocation (9/16/74), 1974 July-October (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Social Responsibility of Organizations in a Free Society (Key Issues Lecture Series, 10/3/74), 1974 October (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Religion and the Purposes of the University (Tenth Anniversary of the Catholic Center, 10/17/74), 1974 October 17 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Social Responsibility of Organizations in a Free Society (75), 1975 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Listing for 1975-1980 as Rector of the UN University (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - United Nations University Speech Materials, [ca. 1975] - 1977 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - United Nations University Rector Inauguration (1/20/75), 1974 December-1975 January (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - University of Pittsburgh Commencement (4/27/75), 1975 April (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Facing the World (University of Pittsburgh Commencement, 4/27/75), 1975 April-May (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - 1975 Commencement (6/5/75), 1975 June 5 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - American Council on Education (10/9/75), 1975 October 9 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - David Owen Memorial Lecture, Cardiff, Wales (5/13/76), 1976 May-1979 May (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - United Nations Economic and Social Council, Geneva (7/23/76), 1976 July 23 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Address to the Japan National Press Club (11/15/76), 1976 November 15 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Address to Harvard-Yale Club (11/16/76), 1976 November 16 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Statement Before the Second Committee of the Thirty-First Session of the General Assembly of the United Nations (11/22/76), 1975 November-1976 November (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - United Nations Administrative Committee on Co-Ordination (ACC, 77), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Second Year of the UN University (Second Committee of the UN General Assembly, 4/11/77), 1977 November-December (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Education About the Real World (Smithsonian Institution, 4/20/77), 1 of 2, 1977 April (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Education About the Real World (Smithsonian Institution, 4/20/77), 2 of 2, 1977 April-May (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - St. Mary's International School and International School of the Sacred Heart Comencement (6/8-9/77), 1977 June 8-9 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - UN University Address at the Western Regional Conference of NGOs on the New Economic and Social Issues Before the UN (9/9/77), 1977 September 9 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - The Second Year of the United Nations University (Programme Commission of UNESCO, 9/19/77), 1977 September 19 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - American School in Japan, 75th Anniversary (9/25/77), 1977 September 25 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Second Year of the UN University (Economic and Social Council of the UN, 10/31/77), 1977 October 31 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - The United Nations University and World Development (Yonsei University, Seoul, 11/18/77), 1977 November 18 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The United Nations University in International Scholarly Co-operation (Tsukuba University, Japan, 12/14/77), 1977 December 14 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Toastmasters at the United Nations University (1/26/78), 1978 January 26 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Knowledge Without Boundaries (Rotary Convention, 5/78), 1978 May-1979 February (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Knowledge Without Boundaries - Printed Materials (Rotary Convention, 5/78), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Knowledge Without Boundaries - Audio Tapes (Rotary Convention, 5/78), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Short Addresses (5/16/78-1/24/79), 1978 May 16-1979 January 24 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Second Committee of General Assembly - Annual Report (10/78), 1978 October (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Statement Before the Programme and External Relations Commission of the UNESCO Executive Board (10/10/78), 1978 October-November (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Asian Symposium on Intellectual Creativity in Endogenous Culture, Kyoto, Japan (11/13/78), 1978 November (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Conference on Energy Alternatives, East West Center, Hawaii (1/9/79), 1979 January 9 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Response to the Toast to the Immortal Bard (1/25/79), 1979 January 25 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Latin American Symposium on Intellectual Creativity in Endogenous Culture, Mexico City (4/23/79), 1979 April 23 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Testimony Before the Senate Governmental Affairs Committee Subcommittee on Energy, Nuclear Proliferation and Federal Services (4/24/79), 1979 March-April (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - World Foot Institute, Iowa State University (4/26/79), 1979 April-August (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - American School in Japan Commencement (6/8/79), 1979 May-June (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - United Nations University Romanian Radio Interview (8/8/79), 1979 August (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - UN Conference on Science and Technology for Development, Vienna (8/22/79), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Statement Before Programme and External Relations Commission of UNESCO Executive Board (10/79), 1979 October (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - The UN University Comes of Age (American Club Women's Group, Tokyo, 11/12/79), 1979 September-November (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - The United Nations University and World Peace (Nihon University, Tokyo, 11/21/79), 1979 July-November (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Leadership in an International Organization (PHP Article, Tokyo, 3/80), 1980 March (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - NYU Alumni Club (3/14/80), 1979 September-1980 September (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - UN University: Record of the First Five Years (Foreign Correspondents' Club, Tokyo, 4/8/80), 1980 February-April (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - The Hague, Rome, Madrid (5/80), 1980 May (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - A Desirable International Outlook for Young Japanese Executives and Educators, Utsonomiya City, Japan (6/4/80), 1980 March-June (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - UN University: The Record of the First Five Years (Soka University, Tokyo, 6/11/80), 1980 March-June (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - International Christian University Convocation (6/12/80), 1980 March-April (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Press Statement (6/27/80), 1980 June 27 (Box 6, Folder 29)